Register of the Poland. Ambasada (Great Britain) Records, 1918-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1919-1945
  - Missing soldiers, Searches for, 1940 (Folder 11)
  - Montreux Conference, 1936 (Folder 12)
  - National minorities in Poland, 1923 (Folder 13)
  - New Zionist Organisation, London, 1937 (Box 69., Folder 1)
  - Notifications, 1939 (Folder 2)
  - Nottingham University, Polish courses, 1938-1939 (Folder 3)
  - Orbis Polish Travel Office, 1938-1939 (Folder 4)
  - Organization of Ukrainian Nationalists (O.U.N.)
    - Pieracki, Bronislaw, Case of, 1932-1934 (Folder 5-6)
    - Terror and sabotage, 1930 (Folder 7)
  - Orthodox Church in Poland, 1938-1939 (Folder 8)
  - Pacifism, 1933 (Folder 9)
  - Pacifist organizations, 1936-1937 (Folder 10)
  - Peace talks between Poland, R.S.F.S.R., and the Ukrainian Socialist Republic, Riga, October 12, 1920 (Box 70., Folder 1)
  - Permanent Court of International Justice at the Hague, 1928, 1935, 1939 (Folder 2)
  - Personnel
    - General
      - 1938 (Folder 3)
      - 1938-1941 (Folder 4)
      - 1940 (Folder 5)
      - 1941 (Folder 6-7)
    - Financial matters, 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
    - Passports, 1940-1941 (Folder 9)
    - Rutkowski, Miecislas, 1940 (Folder 10)
    - Salaries, 1939-1940 (Box 71., Folder 1)
  - Pilsudski, Jozef, Death of, 1935 (Folder 2)
  - Plonka, Leon, 1929 (Folder 3)
  - Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych (Polish Ministry of Foreign Affairs)
    - Biuletyn Narodowosciowy, 1931 (Folder 4)
    - Courses for the staff
      - 1933 (Folder 5)
      - 1935 (Folder 6)
      - 1936 (Folder 7)
      - 1937 (Folder 8)
      - 1938 (Box 72., Folder 1)
      - 1939 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1939-1944 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1942 (Folder 6)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 7)
      - 1942-1944 (Box 73., Folder 1)
      - 1943 (Folder 2)
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 4)
      - Undated (Folder 5)
    - Hoover, Herbert C. (Folder 6)
    - Instructions and correspondence
      - 1919 (Folder 7)
      - 1920 (Folder 8)
      - 1921 (Box 74., Folder 1)
      - 1924 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1925 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1940 (Folder 6)
    - Poland's right to reparations, 1919-1929 (Folder 7)
    - Polish-Soviet relations, 1920-1943 (Box 75., Folder 1-2)
    - Political Department, Protocols, November-December 1920 (Folder 4)
    - Political reports
      - 1933 (Folder 5)
      - 1934 (Polish-German relations) (Folder 6)
    - Polska i Zagranica, 1944
      - 1944-1945 (Box 76., Folder 1)
    - Press Section, reviews, 1920 (Folder 2)
    - Reports
      - 1920 (Folder 3)
      - 1921 (Folder 4)
      - 1921-1922 (reparations) (Folder 5)
    - Review of political events, 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
    - Swiatowy Zwiazek Polakow z Zagranicy, 1933-1935, 1939 (Box 77., Folder 1)
    - Telegrams from Athens
      - 1935-1938 (Folder 2)
      - 1938-1939 (Folder 3)
      - 1939 (Folder 4)
    - Telegrams from various locations, 1937 (Folder 5)
    - Weekly reports, 1920 (Folder 6)
  - Poles deported to the Soviet Union
    - Aid for
      - 1941 (Box 78., Folder 1-2)
      - 1943 (Folder 3)
    - Distribution of, 1941 (Folder 4)
    - Visas for families of the Polish armed forces
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 5)
      - 1943 (Folder 6)
  - Poles in Australia, 1939 (Folder 7)
  - Poles in foreign countries
    - General
      - 1938 (Folder 8)
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 9)
    - Claims, 1938 (Folder 10)
    - Dom Polakow z Zagranicy (Folder 11)
  - Poles in Germany
    - 1920-1930 (Folder 12)
    - 1939 (Folder 13)
  - Poles in Great Britain, 1942 (Folder 14)
  - Poles in Lithuania, 1925 (Box 79., Folder 1)
  - Poles in Trinidad, 1928 (Folder 2)
  - Polish Administrative Office, London, 1942 (Folder 3-4)
  - Polish Air Force
    - General, 1939 (Folder 5-6)
    - Anglo-Polish Agreement, August 5, 1940 (Folder 7-8)
  - Polish armed forces
    - Bomber squadrons for China, 1942 (Box 80., Folder 1)
    - Care of Polish soldiers, 1940 (Folder 2-3)
    - Decorations (medals)
      - 1940-41 (Folder 4)
      - 1942 (Folder 5)
      - 1943 (Folder 6)
    - Second (II) Polish Division in Switzerland, 1941-1942 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Army, supply orders, 1931 (Folder 8)
  - Polish art exhibitions
    - General
      - 1939 (Folder 9)
    - General (Contd.)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 81., Folder 1)
    - Blok Artists Association, 1937-1939 (Folder 2)
  - Polish-British-Soviet relations, 1942 (Folder 3)
  - Polish Commercial and Financial Agency, London, 1919 (Folder 4)
  - Polish Consulate General and Legation in Ottawa, 1942 (Folder 5)
  - Polish Consulate General in Capetown
    - 1930-1934 (Folder 6)
    - 1933-1939 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Consulate General in Dublin
    - General, 1936-1939 (Folder 8)
    - Correspondence
      - 1929-1930 (Folder 9)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 82., Folder 1-3)
    - Economic reports
      - 1929 (Folder 4)
      - 1930 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1930 (Box 83., Folder 1)
      - 1930-1937 (Folder 2)
  - Polish Consulate General in Jerusalem
    - General
      - 1928 (Folder 3)
      - 1930 (Folder 4)
      - 1931 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1932-1935 (Folder 7)
      - 1938-1939 (Folder 8)
    - Jewish emigration, 1939 (Box 84., Folder 1)
    - Press reports
      - 1935 (Folder 2)
      - 1936
        - January-June (Folder 3-4)
        - July-December (Folder 5-6)
      - 1937
        - January-June (Folder 7)
        - July-December (Box 85., Folder 1)
      - 1938 (Folder 2)
  - Polish Consulate General in London
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Folder 3)
    - Economic reports, 1920 (Folder 4-5)
  - Polish Consulate General in Sydney, correspondence and reports, 1922-1923 (Folder 6)
  - Polish Consulate General in Montreal
    - 1927-1928 (Folder 7)
    - 1932-1936, 1940 (Folder 8)
  - Polish Consulate General in Ottawa
    - General
      - 1933-1939 (Box 86., Folder 1)
      - 1939 (Folder 2)
      - 1939-1941 (Folder 3)
    - Economic reports
      - 1935 (Folder 4)
      - 1938 (Folder 5)
  - Polish Consulate in Bagdad, 1939-1940 (Folder 6)
  - Polish Consulate in Bangkok, political reports, 1938-1939 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Consulate in Bombay
    - Economic and political reports, 1934 (Folder 8)
    - Political reports, 1933-1939 (Folder 9)
  - Polish Consulate in Curitiba, 1939 (Folder 10)
  - Polish Consulate in Hong Kong, 1939 (Box 87., Folder 1)
  - Polish Consulate in Riga, 1933 (Folder 2)
  - Polish Consulate in Tel-Aviv
    - General, 1936 (Folder 3-4)
    - Economic reports
      - 1930-1931 (Folder 5)
      - 1934 (Folder 6)
      - 1935 (Folder 7-8)
      - 1937-1939 (Folder 9)
  - Polish consulates in Canada (Winnipeg and Montreal), correspondence, 1920 (Box 88., Folder 1)
  - Polish courses taught at various British schools, 1939 (Folder 2)
  - Polish-Czech relations
    - General
      - 1931 (Folder 3)
      - 1935 (Folder 4)
      - 1937-1938 (Folder 5)
      - 1938 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 8-9)
      - 1941 (Folder 10)
      - 1941 (Box 89., Folder 1)
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 2-3)
      - 1942 (Folder 4-6)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 7)
    - Cieszyn (Teschen Silesia), 1938 (Folder 8)
    - German-occupied territories, 1941-1942 (Folder 9)
    - German-occupied territories, 1941-1942 (Box 90., Folder 1)
  - Polish Delegation to the Paris Peace Conference, 1919-1920 (Folder 2-3)
  - Polish doctors and health care of Poles in Great Britain, 1940-1941 (Folder 4)
  - Polish economic relations with Great Britain and the United States, 1935 (Folder 5)
  - Polish education, literature, entertainment, 1939 (Folder 6)
  - Polish Embassy at the Vatican, 1929 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Embassy in Bucharest, 1936-39 (Folder 8)
  - Polish Embassy in Germany (Berlin)
    - 1934-1938 (Folder 9)
    - Poland in the German press, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - Polish Embassy in Moscow
    - Correspondence
      - 1935-1936 (Folder 11)
      - 1936-1938 (Folder 12)
    - Report, 1937 (Box 91., Folder 1)
  - Polish Embassy in Paris
    - Correspondence and reports
      - 1924 (Folder 2)
      - 1925
        - January-April (Folder 3)
        - May-June (Folder 4)
        - July-August (Folder 5)
        - September-December (Folder 6)
    - Financial reports, 1935 (Folder 7)
    - Political reports
      - 1931 (Folder 8)
      - 1932 (Folder 9)
      - 1933 (Box 92., Folder 1)
      - 1935 (Folder 2)
      - 1936 (Folder 3)
      - 1937
        - January-May (Folder 4)
        - June-December (Folder 5)
      - 1938 (Folder 6)
      - 1938-1939 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Embassy in Rome, correspondence and reports
    - 1925 (Folder 8)
    - 1925 (Box 93., Folder 1)
    - 1931 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 4)
    - 1936-1937 (Folder 5)
    - 1938 (Folder 6-7)
    - 1939 (Folder 8)
  - Polish Embassy in Tokyo, correspondence, 1936-1939 (Sino-Japanese conflict) (Folder 9)
  - Polish Embassy in Turkey, 1937 (Box 94., Folder 1)
  - Polish Embassy in Washington, D.C.
    - Correspondence and reports
      - 1937 (Folder 2)
      - 1938 (Folder 3)
      - 1942 (Folder 4)
    - Political reports
      - 1928, 1930-1931 (Folder 5)
      - 1932 (Folder 6)
      - 1933 (Folder 7)
      - 1939 (Folder 8)
    - Press reports, 1936 (Folder 9)
  - Polish engineers in Canada, 1941 (Folder 10)
  - Polish engineers in Great Britain
    - 1941 (Folder 11)
    - 1941-1942 (Folder 12)
  - Polish exhibitions in Great Britain, 1942 (Folder 13)
  - Polish Exiles Protection, London
    - 1916 (Box 95., Folder 1)
    - 1917 (Folder 2-4)
  - Polish films and photographs
    - 1939 (Folder 5-6)
    - 1942 (Folder 7)
  - Polish-German Commercial Agreement, March 1930 (Box 96., Folder 1)
  - Polish-German economic relations, 1931-1933 (Folder 2)
  - Polish-German relations
    - 1919 (Folder 3)
    - 1920 (Folder 4)
    - 1937-1938 (Folder 5)
  - Polish Hospital in Edinburgh (Paderewski Fund), 1941 (Folder 6)
  - Polish-Hungarian relations, 1938 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Information Bureau, Montreal, 1939 (Folder 8)
  - Polish Information Committee, London, 1920 (Folder 9)
  - Polish Jews in Great Britain (Jewish organizations in Great Britain)
    - 1934 (Folder 10)
    - 1935 (Box 97., Folder 1)
    - 1936 (Folder 2)
    - 1937 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1941 (Folder 5)
  - Polish Jews in Great Britain and Palestine, 1940 (Folder 6-7)
  - Polish Legation at the Hague, 1939 (Folder 8)
  - Polish Legation in Athens, 1921 (Box 98., Folder 1)
  - Polish Legation in Belgrade, 1920 (Folder 2)
  - Polish Legation in Berlin
    - 1921-1923 (Folder 3)
    - 1931 (Folder 4-6)
    - 1932 (Folder 7)
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 8)
  - Polish Legation in Berne
    - Correspondence and reports, 1939 (Folder 9)
    - Reports, 1920 (Box 99., Folder 1)
    - Telegrams, 1930-1939 (Folder 2)
  - Polish Legation in Brussels
    - Correspondence and reports, 1925 (Folder 3)
    - Reports, 1935-1939 (Folder 4)
  - Polish Legation in Bucharest, 1920-1921 (Folder 5)
  - Polish Legation in Budapest, 1921 (Folder 6)
  - Polish Legation in Buenos-Aires, 1939 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Legation in Cairo
    - General
      - 1938 (Folder 8)
      - 1939 (Folder 9)
    - Possibility of colonization in Transjordania, 1939 (Folder 10)
  - Polish Legation in Constantinople, 1920-1922 (Folder 11)
  - Polish Legation in Copenhagen, 1938 (Folder 12)
  - Polish Legation in Helsingfors, 1937-1939 (Folder 13)
  - Polish Legation in Lisbon, 1936-1939 (Folder 14)
  - Polish Legation in Madrid, 1921 (Folder 15)
  - Polish Legation in Mexico, 1938 (Folder 16)
  - Polish Legation in Paris, 1921-1922 (Box 100., Folder 1)
  - Polish Legation in Rio de Janeiro, 1931 (Folder 2)
  - Polish Legation in Sofia
    - Reports, 1921 (Folder 3)
    - Telegrams, 1932-1939 (Folder 4)
  - Polish Legation in Stockholm, 1937-1939 (Folder 5)
  - Polish Legation in Vienna, 1920-1921 (Folder 6)
  - Polish-Lithuanian relations
    - 1938-1939 (Folder 7)
    - 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
  - Polish mercantile and shipping fleets
    - 1939-1940 (Folder 9)
    - 1940 (Box 101., Folder 1)
    - 1941 (Folder 2)
  - Polish musical performances, 1939 (Folder 3)
  - Polish National Committee, Paris
    - Correspondence, 1918-1919 (Folder 4)
    - Press review, March-April 1919 (Folder 5)
  - Polish National Committee, London
    - Brocton Camp, 1919 (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence relating to Polish exiles, 1919 (Box 102., Folder 1)
    - Feltham Camp, 1919 (Folder 2-3)
    - Holyport Camp, 1919 (Folder 4)
    - List of Polish exiles, 1918 (Folder 5)
    - List of wounded Polish exiles, 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
    - Reports relating to Polish exiles, 1918 (Folder 7)
    - Review of the British press, April-May 1919 (Box 103., Folder 1)
  - Polish National Loan (Pozyczka Narodowa), 1933-1934. Includes prints (Folder 2)
  - Polish Naval Headquarters, London, reports, 1943 (Folder 3)
  - Polish Navy, 1934-1938 (Folder 4)
  - Polish Press Bureau in London, News from Poland,October-December 1939 (Folder 5)
  - Polish prisoners of war in France
    - 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
    - 1919 (Folder 7)
    - 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
  - Polish publications in Great Britain, 1943 (Box 104., Folder 1)
  - Polish relief debts
    - 1924
      - January-July (Folder 2)
      - August-December (Folder 3)
    - 1925-1928 (Folder 4)
    - 1930-1933 (Folder 5)
    - 1933-1934 (Folder 6)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 105., Folder 1)
  - Polish Relief Fund
    - 1939 (Folder 2)
    - 1942 (Folder 3-4)
  - Polish Research Centre, London
    - 1939 (Folder 5)
    - 1940 (Folder 6)
    - 1941 (Folder 7)
  - Polish scientists, 1925 (Box 106., Folder 1)
  - Polish scouts (Folder 2)
  - Polish Socialist Party, 1920 (Folder 3)
  - Polish soldiers and families in Great Britain, 1940 (Folder 4)
  - Polish-Soviet relations
    - General, 1927-1933 (Folder 5)
    - Association for International Understanding, 1925-1928 (Folder 6)
    - Eastern frontier of Poland, 1926 (Folder 7)
    - Economic conditions in the Soviet Union, 1931 (Folder 8)
  - Polish Stabilization Loan
    - 1928-1934 (Folder 9)
    - 1934-1935 (Folder 10)
    - 1935 (Folder 11)
    - 1935 (Box 107., Folder 1)
    - 1936 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1937
      - January-February (Folder 4)
      - March-July (Folder 5)
      - August-October (Folder 6)
      - November-December (Folder 7)
    - 1938
      - January-May (Box 108., Folder 1-2)
      - June-December (Folder 3)
  - Polish State Mint - Silver purchase, 1936-1937 (Folder 4)
  - Polish State Railways (Polskie Koleje Panstwowe)
    - General
      - Undated (Folder 5)
      - 1934 (Folder 6)
      - 1935 (Folder 7)
      - 1934-1936 (Box 109., Folder 1)
      - 1936 (Folder 2)
    - Electrification loans
      - 1933 (Folder 3)
      - 1937 (Folder 4)
      - 1937-1938 (Folder 5)
      - 1938-1939 (Folder 6)
  - Polish-Swedish relations, 1938-1939 (Folder 7)
  - Polish Tatra Society - Climbing expedition to the Himalayas, 1939 (Folder 8)
  - Polish tobacco monopoly, 1924-1935 (Box 110., Folder 1)
  - Polish travelers abroad
    - 1938 (Folder 2)
    - 1939 (Folder 3-4)
  - Political reports
    - General
      - 1931 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1932 (Folder 7)
      - 1935-1936 (Folder 8)
      - 1937 (Folder 9)
      - 1937 (Box 111., Folder 1)
      - 1938 (Folder 2-4)
      - 1939 (Folder 5)
    - Spain
      - 1931 (Folder 6)
      - 1936-1937 (Folder 7-8)
      - 1939 (Folder 9)
  - Polska Informacja Polityczna
    - 1936 (Box 112., Folder 1-2)
    - 1937 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1938 (Folder 5-6)
    - 1939 (Folder 7)
  - Polskie Biuro Badan Politycznych (Polish Bureau of Political Research), 1940 (Folder 8)
  - Pomerania, 1934 (Folder 9)
  - Potocki, Count (of Montalk) (Box 113., Folder 1)
  - Press agencies abroad, 1939 (Folder 2)
  - Press Bureau, 1920 (Folder 3)
  - Press in Poland, 1939 (Folder 4-6)
  - Press reports
    - 1932 (Folder 7)
    - 1939 March-November (Folder 8)
  - Press reports from various Polish diplomatic posts
    - 1939-1940 (Folder 9)
    - 1940 (Box 114., Folder 1)
  - Propaganda in the press, 1933 (Folder 2)
  - Property
    - 47 Portland Place (Folder 3)
    - 51-53 New Cavendish Street (Attaches' homes) (Folder 4)
  - Protestant churches in Poland, 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Public welfare in Poland, 1938-1939 (Folder 6)
  - Publications about Poland
    - 1939 (Folder 7-8)
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 9)
    - 1942 (Folder 10)
    - 1942 (Box 115., Folder 1)
    - 1943 (Folder 2-3)
  - Publications exchanges, 1938-39 (Folder 4)
  - Raczynski, Edward - Conversations with Winston Churchill, Anthony Eden, and others, 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
  - Radio communiques, July 1940 (Folder 6)
  - Radio equipment, 1939 (Folder 7-8)
  - Refugees from Poland
    - 1939 (Box 116., Folder 1)
    - 1940 (Folder 2-3)
  - Relief for Poland, 1941-1943 (Folder 4)
  - Relief for Poland and Poles in other countries, 1939 (Folder 5-6)
  - Relief organizations, 1919 (Folder 7-8)
  - Relief organizations, 1919 (Box 117., Folder 1)
  - Relief to Polish flood victims, 1934-1945 (Folder 2)
  - Relief work for Polish exiles
    - 1918-1919 (Folder 3)
    - 1920 (Folder 4)
  - Repatriations
    - General
      - 1919 (Folder 5)
      - 1920-1922 (Folder 6)
    - American and Canadian Poles, 1920 (Folder 7)
    - Poles from Egypt, 1919-1922 (Box 118., Folder 1)
    - Poles from Great Britain
      - General
        - 1918 December-1919 August (Folder 2)
        - 1919
          - September (Folder 3)
          - October (Folder 4)
          - November-December (Folder 5)
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
      - List of, 1918-1919 (Box 119., Folder 1)
    - Poles from India, 1919-1921 (Folder 2-3)
    - Poles from Italy, 1919-1920 (Folder 4)
    - Poles from the Soviet Union
      - Arkhangel'sk, Murmansk, 1919 (Folder 5)
      - Vladivostok, 1920-1922 (Folder 6)
    - War prisoners (Nansen Mission), 1920 (Box 120., Folder 1)
  - Rotowski, Arnold (Folder 2)
  - Royal Institute of International Affairs, Information Department, memorandum on Anglo-Iraq relations, 1931 (Folder 3)
  - Russian Bank for Foreign Trade, 1935 (Folder 4)
  - Russian refugees in Poland, 1922 (Folder 5)
  - Ruthenia, 1938 (Folder 6)
  - Rutkowski, Mieceslas de (Folder 7)
  - Saar Basin Territory
    - 1920 (Folder 8-9)
    - 1934 (Box 121., Folder 1)
  - Serbo-Lusatian Association, London, 1942-1943 (Folder 2)
  - Shipping
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Folder 3)
    - Gdynia-America Shipping Lines, 1937 (Folder 4)
    - Lloyds Register of Shipping, 1938-1939 (Folder 5)
    - Passenger numbers certificates, 1936-1939 (Folder 6)
  - "Short Account of Military and Naval Operations in the Netherlands from 10-14th May, 1940" (Folder 7)
  - Sikorski, Wladyslaw
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Gibraltar catastrophe, July 5, 1943 (Folder 9)
  - Sino-Japanese Conflict, 1937 (Box 122., Folder 1)
  - Sino-Japanese relations, 1934-1935 (Folder 2)
  - Slawinski, M. Tadeusz (Folder 3)
  - Smigly-Rydz, Marshal, speech, August 6, 1939 (Folder 4)
  - Soviet occupation of Eastern Poland, 1943 (Folder 5-6)
  - Soviet occupation of Poland, Wilno and Kowno regions, 1941 (Folder 7-8)
  - Soviet Union
    - Economic conditions, 1925 (Folder 9)
    - Financial obligations, 1920-1922 (Folder 10)
    - Polish Legation in Khar'kov, 1922-1924 (Box 123., Folder 1-2)
    - Polish Legation in Moscow, 1922-1923 (Folder 3)
    - Religion, 1922 (Folder 4)
    - Trade agreements, 1921 (Folder 5)
  - Sports in Poland, 1939 (Folder 6)
  - Sprawy Sowieckie (Soviet Affairs), review of Soviet press, 1940 (Folder 7-8)
  - Study tours in Poland (cancelled), 1939 (Folder 9)
  - Subscriptions, 1939 (Folder 10)
  - Telegrams, list of, 1931-1936 (Box 124., Folder 1)
  - Tobacco loan, 1924 (Folder 2)
  - Tourism and travel in Poland, 1939 (Folder 3)
  - Trade and Commerce Agreement between Poland and Great Britain, London, February 1935
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Negotiations, 1933-1935 (Folder 5-7)
    - Negotiations, 1933-1935 (Box 125., Folder 1-3)
  - Transit through German waterways (Kiel Canal), 1936-1937 (Folder 4)
  - Transit through Poland (Pomerania, Niemen River), 1930-1936 (Folder 5)
  - Treaty between Poland and Afghanistan, 1927 (Folder 6)
  - Treaty between Poland and Persia, 1927 (Folder 7)
  - Ukrainian cooperatives, 1922 (Folder 8)
  - Ukrainian national movements, 1917-1927 (Folder 9)
  - Ukrainian organizations, political parties, schools, 1925 (Folder 10)
  - Ukrainian petitions to the League of Nations
    - 1930 (Box 126., Folder 1)
    - 1931 (Folder 2)
    - 1932 (Folder 3)
  - Ukrainian press in the United States
    - 1940-1941 (Folder 4)
    - 1940, 1942 (Folder 5)
    - 1941 (Folder 6)
  - Ukrainians
    - 1929-1931 (Box 127., Folder 1)
    - 1936 (Folder 2)
    - Felinski, M., "Ukraincy w Polsce Odrodzonej," n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Ukrainians in Canada
    - 1934 (Folder 4)
    - 1938-1939 (Folder 5)
    - 1939 (Folder 6)
    - 1940 (Folder 7)
    - 1941 (Folder 8)
  - Ukrainians in Poland and abroad, 1939 (Box 128., Folder 1-3)
  - Ukrainians in the Polish Sejm, 1923-1924 (Folder 4)
  - University of Birmingham
    - Polish courses, 1938-1939 (Folder 5)
    - Publications on Poland
      - 1936-1938 (Folder 6)
      - 1938-1939 (Box 129., Folder 1)
  - University of London. School of Slavonic and East European Studies
    - Correspondence
      - 1932-1934 (Folder 2)
      - 1938-1939 (Folder 3)
      - 1942 (Folder 4)
    - Lectures on Poland, 1933-1934 (Folder 5)
  - Upper Silesia
    - 1921 (Folder 6)
    - 1929-1931 (Folder 7)
    - 1937 (Folder 8)
  - Vatican, 1936 (Folder 9)
  - Visas, 1941
    - January-February (Folder 10)
    - March (Folder 11)
    - April (Box 130., Folder 1)
    - May (Folder 2)
    - June-July (Folder 3)
    - August (Folder 4)
    - September (Folder 5)
    - October-November (Folder 6)
    - November-December (Folder 7)
  - Visas for refugees, 1939 (Folder 8)
  - Visas for refugees, 1939 (Box 131., Folder 1)
  - War criminals
    - 1942 (Folder 2)
    - 1943 (Folder 3)
  - Warsaw uprising, maps, August-September 1944 (Folder 4)
  - Wheat Advisory Committee
    - 1934 (Folder 5)
    - 1938 (Folder 6)
    - 1939 (Folder 7)
    - 1939 (Box 132., Folder 1-4)
  - Wiadomosci Codzienne z Prasy Zydowskiej, Warsaw, 1935 (Folder 5)
  - Wiadomosci Ukrainskie, Warsaw, 1935 (Folder 6)
  - Wilno, Evacuation of Poles from, 1941 (Folder 7)
  - World Alliance for Combating Anti-Semitism, 1933 (Folder 8)
  - Wyderka, Julian (Box 133., Folder 1)
  - Yemeni flag, 1936-1937 (Folder 2)
  - Zwiazek Poludniowo-Afrykanski (South African Union), 1938 (Folder 3)
  - Miscellany (Folder 4-8)